Folder inventory to the Marcus Raskin papers, 1952-2013 MS2297
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- The Liberal Project, 1952-2013; Series 9
  - Correspondence, research and writings, 1954-2013; Series 9 Subseries 2
    This subseries spans from 1954-2013 and includes correspondence, memos, press releases, essays, and articles related to the Liberal Project, of which Marcus Raskin was the secretary. The Liberal Project started in the late 1950s-early 1960s and was comprised of scholars, scientists and experts, and political leaders who sought to redefine the term liberalism and better apply it to current events. Topics addressed within the project included International Relations, Law and the Judiciary, Education, Science and Culture, Economic and Industrial Affairs, and Defense Policy. The Liberal Project also published many of their essays in a 1962 book, "The Liberal Papers."
    - Correspondence: Doubleday and Company, Inc. Publishers, 1960; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Institute for International Order, 1960; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Nobel Peace Prize, 1960; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - [Correspondence: General], 1959-1962, 2000; 1959-1962; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - [Correspondence: General], 1960; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - [Correspondence: General], 1960-1961; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Writings: Wisconsin History, 1960-1962; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Writings: Wisconsin History, 1963-1965; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Writings: Wisconsin History, 1966-1969; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Research: Budget Study - Washington, D.C., 1982; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Research: Civil Defense Documents, 1961-1962; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Research: Domestic Affairs/Miscellaneous Documents, 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Research: Duplicate Documents, 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Research: Education Documents, 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Research: Foreign Policy Documents - National Security Council, 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Research: Nuclear History Documents - National Security Council, 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - [Research: General], 1954-1960; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Writings: Common Good, 1987; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Writings: Handwritten Notes, 1974; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Writings: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), 1968-1981; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Writings: Raskin Interviews, 1994-1999; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Writings: Lectures and Events, 1984-1987; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Writings: US-USSR Conference Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1983; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Writings: "The Theory and Practice of Deterrence", 1962; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Writings: By Marc Raskin and Collected by Him (1/2), 1961-1963, 2010; 1961-1963; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Writings: By Marc Raskin and Collected By Him (2/2), 1960-1962, 2013; 1960-1962; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - The Liberal Project, 1952-1970; Series 9 Subseries 3
    This subseries spans from 1952-1970 and contains general correspondence, works written and collected by Marcus Raskin on the topics for the Liberal Project, and articles and programs for various lectures and conferences he attended. It also includes organized files with outlines of Raskin's correspondence and memos in the Wisconsin History folders.
    - Congressional Communications, 1960-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1961; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Democracy A Social Power Analysis" by John Atlee, 1952; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Liberalism Book, 1952, 1960; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Liberalism Miscellaneous, 1959-1970; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Liberal Papers Book, 1959-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Liberal Papers Book, 1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Liberal Project Members, 1959-1961; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Seymour Melman Writings, 1960-1961; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Syllabus, 1959-1960; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1958-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1959-1960; Series 9 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1959-1961; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1959-1961; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1959-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1960-1961; Sreies 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1960-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1961-1962; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - [Liberal Project: General], 1964; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 18, Folder 20)